[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa41", "question": "In what Australian state would you find Canberra?", "answer": "Australian Capital Territory", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada0", "question": "Who was better known as \"Sundance Kid\"?", "answer": "Harry Alonzo Longabaugh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd668d1a5bfecdd737e0873", "question": "What was the name of the Beatles' first studio album?", "answer": "Cargo House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d27", "question": "What children's books character is scared of Heffalumps and Woozles?", "answer": "Winnie the Pooh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c3", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Krusty Gets Busted\", according to Bart, what do all good-hearted people have?", "answer": "Small feet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c76", "question": "What philosopher/author lived on the shores of Walden Pond?", "answer": "Henry David Thoreau", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c66f", "question": "What type of bridge is the Golden Gate Bridge?", "answer": "Suspension bridge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fa", "question": "What is the common name for the fruit Citrus grandis?", "answer": "Grapefruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133896f", "question": "What zoo animals were set free in the title of John Irving's first novel?", "answer": "Bears", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b1744b5bb2d29f81593b6fc", "question": "In the 1986 movie \"Aliens\", what was Newt's real name?", "answer": "Rebecca Jorden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2cc", "question": "Which 1947 film, starring Cary Grant and Loretta Young was directed by Henry Koster?", "answer": "The Bishop's Wife", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358b6d5db0d66a186cb557", "question": "Falcon State is located in which South American country?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e19a06d333868d34d728", "question": "How long was Francisco Franco in power in Spain?", "answer": "36 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c9b49076251badbead8", "question": "Who was the first American to orbit the Earth?", "answer": "John Glenn -- He orbited the Earth three times in five hours in a Mercury space capsule he named \"Friendship 7\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec24ca8dc25ca9e12ef63b", "question": "What was the very first Andrew Lloyd Webber musical to be adapted to film?", "answer": "Jesus Christ Superstar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8d", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Gettysburg\" based on?", "answer": "The Killer Angels", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecdd3eec223966ae8f8902", "question": "Who is the godmother of Kurt Cobain and Courtney Love's kid Francis Bean?", "answer": "Drew Barrymore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078bd40eee65b76b9f266d", "question": "What was the name of the first English child born in the Americas?", "answer": "Virginia Dare (She was born August 18, 1587 in\u00a0Roanoke Colony.  She and about 120 settlers mysteriously disappeared.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69d4320565ad31a57c776", "question": "In medieval Scotland, what was a \"Gaberlunzie\"?", "answer": "A formerly-licensed beggar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d1", "question": "Who wrote \"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\"?", "answer": "Roald Dahl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c593", "question": "What\u2019s a tropical cyclone called when its winds reach 74 miles per hour?", "answer": "A Hurricane", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65c4c1f3c0ead6880d611", "question": "To what British politician was Princess Diana directly related?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339399", "question": "How many brothers did Ryan lose in the movie \"Saving Private Ryan\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e59", "question": "In the 1996 movie, what kind of animal shares Joe's Apartment with him?", "answer": "Cockroaches", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397df", "question": "What are the first names of the two British comics Little and Large?", "answer": "Syd and Eddie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ce", "question": "What is the lowest point in the United States?", "answer": "Death Valley, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339337", "question": "How many children did Lucy and Desi have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad77", "question": "Who was the first person to fly solo across the Atlantic ocean?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339531", "question": "What show debuted in 1963 and became the longest running sci-fi series?", "answer": "Doctor Who", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b32", "question": "Who is the one-eyed giant of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Cyclops", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2fb", "question": "Who has held the world record in the pole vault, 6.14 m, for more than twenty years?", "answer": "Sergei Bubka", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff5176dff04d658268c92fb", "question": "What was traditionally painted on the eastern side of a sarcophagus?", "answer": "Eyes (The eastern side was often painted with eyes because it was believed that the deceased could still watch the rising sun.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ead", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"The Score\"?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5902a0a9cad1ec93f27df76f", "question": "Who is credited with inventing the AeroPress?", "answer": "Alan Adler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b657", "question": "What company introduced the first radio with push-button tuning in 1927?", "answer": "Zenith", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc5b", "question": "\"Cirque du Soleil\" was founded in what Canadian province?", "answer": "Quebec", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea77bfff048f679a45abce", "question": "Meningitis is characterized by what major symptoms?", "answer": "Stiff neck, sudden high fever and a severe headache", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e7e106d333868d34d744", "question": "A purple stripe on a Roman tunic was a sign of what?", "answer": "Status", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a273", "question": "Who was the male star of the 1997 film \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "Leonardo DiCaprio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedd9e96ce05a3942286d7e", "question": "What was the name of the girl in the film \"Jurassic Park\"?", "answer": "Lex Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d5", "question": "What European city is known as the \"Eternal City\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071dc23745b36be73039dc", "question": "What is the nationality of the first woman in space?", "answer": "Soviet/Russian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d1", "question": "How did Norman E. Shumway make medical history?", "answer": "He performed the first successful transplant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f433fa5fdd6dd25324de", "question": "Ornamental railings on a balcony are called what?", "answer": "Balustrade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523e3f736d4be723796b4d", "question": "Which region of Canada would you find Canada\u2019s Technology Triangle?", "answer": "Waterloo Region", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3f88ff048f679a45ab60", "question": "What type of birthmark is also called a stork bite?", "answer": "Salmon Patches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b7abb2c6490a8cc1a6e5294", "question": "In computer programming, which logic gate outputs TRUE if both inputs are TRUE?", "answer": "AND", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f7", "question": "What was the name of the first orbiter of NASA's space shuttle program?", "answer": "Enterprise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6aac820565ad31a57c821", "question": "Who was the most decorated American soldier during World War II?", "answer": "Audie L Murphy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a326", "question": "Who directed the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Walter Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e3", "question": "What \u201cStar Trek\u201d character had a name meaning \u201cfreedom\u201d in Swahili?", "answer": "Uhura", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa63", "question": "Mauritania is in which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ae", "question": "The Great Pee Dee River flows into what body of water?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c99c", "question": "What is the more common name for the star cluster, Pleiades?", "answer": "Seven Sisters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eef", "question": "What H. G. Wells title would become a Ralph Ellison novel without the initial \"the\"?", "answer": "The Invisible Man", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba70", "question": "Gouda cheese comes from what country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394ba", "question": "What \"Twilight Zone\" writer also created \"The New People\" in 1969?", "answer": "Rod Serling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b478", "question": "The Battle of the Plains of Abraham was fought outside which city?", "answer": "Quebec City", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed6", "question": "The Titanic picked up passengers in which\u00a0two\u00a0ports other than Southampton?", "answer": "Cherbourg and Queenstown", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff146e2b0ee8c595b6d39c1", "question": "What is the oldest operating Broadway theater?", "answer": "The Lyceum Theater", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133982d", "question": "What musical follows the rivalry between the Jets and the Sharks in New York City?", "answer": "West Side Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600242894be4723ccac22188", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Don Quixote\"?", "answer": "Miguel de Cervantes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0c", "question": "What is the primary ingredient in Soy Sauce, besides water?", "answer": "Wheat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc4", "question": "What Best Picture-winning film was adapted from the short story collection \"Rope Burns\"?", "answer": "Million Dollar Baby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339243", "question": "What is the main character's job in the movie \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "Archeologist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338972", "question": "Where does Harry Potter have a lightning-shaped scar?", "answer": "On his forehead", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be57fff5415ba52ed6f0ab0", "question": "Which TV show was set in the fictional town of Dunn's River, Connecticut?", "answer": "Soap", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abdd", "question": "Which famous city bridge is known locally as \"The Coathanger\"?", "answer": "Sydney Harbour Bridge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339901", "question": "What was Herbie the Lovebug's racing number?", "answer": "53", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b3", "question": "What lake was created when the Bagnell Dam was built across the Osage River?", "answer": "Lake of the Ozarks", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a9", "question": "Who considered founding a utopian art colony at Arles in France prior to his suicide?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8acb601dd7bf43be5e770", "question": "Stollen is a traditional fruit-and-nut holiday bread from which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f719ca9e54d890926f6e2", "question": "In geography, what is a skerry?", "answer": "A small rocky island.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fffa6e873838c5c8a417f33", "question": "Which is the most dangerous tree in the world?", "answer": "Manchineel tree (Found in the Florida Everglades and coastal Caribbean, its sap will cause blisters with the slightest contact.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5bf", "question": "Yellowstone Lake is located in which US state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b878", "question": "What color does the bride commonly wear in China?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c120", "question": "What is the fear of sleep known as?", "answer": "Somniphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a48e", "question": "What is the largest city of Madeira?", "answer": "Funchal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392dc", "question": "What duo's debut album was titled \"Wednesday Morning, 3 AM\"?", "answer": "Simon & Garfunkel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338edf", "question": "What famous name in opera was the son-in-law of composer Franz Liszt?", "answer": "Richard Wagner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391bd", "question": "What is Sean Connery's real first name?", "answer": "Thomas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb64f25dad637d903c8832", "question": "Where is the world's longest golf course?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f0", "question": "Carly Simon was once married to what other Adult Contemporary singer?", "answer": "James Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d04", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Paul Shaffer?", "answer": "David Letterman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dda", "question": "What army is invading Pepperland in the Beatles film \"Yellow Submarine\"?", "answer": "The Blue Meanies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febbc557e83c707845b214b", "question": "Which NFL player later went on to become a US Supreme Court Judge?", "answer": "Byron White who was a runner-up to the Heisman Trophy in 1937, served as an Associate Supreme Court Justice from 1962 to 1993.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a0", "question": "What is Ethiopia's main commercial crop?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbea", "question": "Jean Paul Gaultier was hired as an assistant to what popular designer?", "answer": "Pierre Cardin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b7", "question": "What 18 year old songstress did Kentwood, Louisiana, honor with her own museum in 2000?", "answer": "Britney Spears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69fc820565ad31a57c790", "question": "Where did the \u201cwiki\u201d in Wikipedia come from?", "answer": "Hawaiian for \"fast\" or \"quick\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a80", "question": "Who wrote the novel Oryx and Crake?", "answer": "Margaret Atwood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b985", "question": "What name is given to the vertical bar of a window?", "answer": "Mullion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392fa", "question": "In the movie \"Bullitt\", what car does Steve McQueen drive?", "answer": "Ford Mustang", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc0", "question": "What is the third movement of a symphony called?", "answer": "Minuet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a969", "question": "What California peak, which erupted in 1915, is the world's largest lava dome?", "answer": "Lassen Peak", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b34ce662d71a53650fdd", "question": "Who wrote the opening line, \"All children, except one, grow up\"?", "answer": "J.M. Barrie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5cd40be1685cf15b733e988c", "question": "Which cartoon family lives in 742 Evergreen Terrace, Springfield, USA?", "answer": "The Simpsons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa5446ce05a3942286ebc", "question": "In the film \"Airplane!\", what was the name of Leslie Nelson's character?", "answer": "Dr. Alan Rumack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e87106d333868d34d748", "question": "Authorities in which country released gas into a theater, killing 116 hostages in 2002?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339346", "question": "What TV show did Tom Hanks appear on for two seasons?", "answer": "Bosom Buddies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389da", "question": "What war saw the bombing of Guernica that inspired one of Picasso's most moving paintings?", "answer": "Spanish Civil War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d7a", "question": "The BBC once banned The Beatles' \"Come Together\" for \"advertising\" what product in the lyrics?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c99d", "question": "The star cluster, \"Seven Sisters\", is also known as what?", "answer": "Pleiades", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600240f84be4723ccac2216d", "question": "In the novel \"Dances with Wolves,\" what name does John Dunbar give to the wolf he befriends?", "answer": "\"Two Socks\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad0", "question": "What does a nephologist study?", "answer": "Clouds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c44a", "question": "How many chromosomes does a donkey have?", "answer": "62", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa39a6ce05a3942286ea5", "question": "What was the name of the Today Show's chimpanzee mascot?", "answer": "J. Fred Muggs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2fc", "question": "Where did the world's tallest bird, the giant moa, live until it went extinct around 1500?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339518", "question": "What movie earned John Wayne his first Academy Award?", "answer": "True Grit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017370a44491cbd7c5a1783", "question": "Hugin and Munin were raven spirits that accompanied which Nordic figure?", "answer": "The ravens Hugin and Munin (meaning \"thought\" and \"memory\") are said to sit on the shoulders of the Nordic god Odin.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4da", "question": "Which is larger, a baseball or a softball?", "answer": "A softball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8adf901dd7bf43be5e781", "question": "Pinto Colvig is better known as the original what?", "answer": "Bozo the clown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afdf", "question": "In the year 1900, what killed over 8,000 people in Galveston, Texas?", "answer": "Hurricane", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec234a8dc25ca9e12ef62f", "question": "By what name is \"Calcium oxide\" more commonly known?", "answer": "Quicklime", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b4", "question": "In Greek mythology what is the place of ideal happiness called?", "answer": "Elysium", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f7", "question": "Who played Roseanne\u2019s sister, Jackie, on the TV show \u201cRoseanne\u201d?", "answer": "Laurie Metcalf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b901", "question": "What sportsmen are divided into naturals and goofy-foots?", "answer": "Surfers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339499", "question": "In what city did Ann Romano raise her two daughters on the show \"One Day at a Time\"?", "answer": "Indianapolis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b334", "question": "Who was the last King of Troy?", "answer": "Priam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133961a", "question": "The \"Sacred Order of the Stonecutters\" was a fictional club in which TV show?", "answer": "The Simpsons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6f", "question": "Who wrote the music to \"West Side Story\"?", "answer": "Leonard Bernstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b552", "question": "What colour M&Ms did not exist from 1976 to 1987?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae7c", "question": "What nickname was given to Al Capone?", "answer": "Scarface", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab99b8221a8909e5c332d2c", "question": "When was the film \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\" released?", "answer": "1988", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb8", "question": "What common office supply item is named for the Asian \"abaca\" fiber used to make them?", "answer": "Manila envelopes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c825", "question": "What common aquarium fish is named for the naturalist who discovered it in Trinidad in 1876?", "answer": "The guppy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f6fcda9e54d890926f6d3", "question": "The southernmost city in the world is located in which country?", "answer": "Chile -- Ushuaia, Argentina held the title until 2019, when Chilean authorities upgraded the town Puerto Williams to city status.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15b", "question": "What popular figure was born Agnese Gonxhe Bojaxhiu?", "answer": "Mother Teresa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a320", "question": "In which 2003 film did Hugh Grant play the British Prime Minister?", "answer": "Love Actually", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea4341ff048f679a45ab80", "question": "What is the maximum number of electrons possible in the 6th energy level?", "answer": "72", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133905d", "question": "What year did poet Sylvia Plath die?", "answer": "1963", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a880", "question": "What Manhattan intersection was America's first transfer circle?", "answer": "Columbus Circle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae27", "question": "Which famous explorer was killed in the Hawaiian Islands in 1779?", "answer": "James Cook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3de", "question": "What city is the capital of Turkey?", "answer": "Ankara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c9", "question": "What are the three primary ingredients in a standard Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Creme de Menthe, Creme de Cacao and fresh cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078b270eee65b76b9f2663", "question": "What was the original name for battle tanks?", "answer": "Landships (The name \"tank\" was due to the secrecy about its development project, which was leaked as research into water tanks.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7fe", "question": "Which planet was originally known as the Georgian Star?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f16738f7c52aae91cc07b6", "question": "What is the capital of Guinea-Bissau?", "answer": "Bissau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c88e9da22f44c2d77a29c49", "question": "What organization was formed at the Bretton Woods Conference in 1944", "answer": "The International Monetary Fund", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c0", "question": "From which country did the smorgasbord originate?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cea1877e98cb97778a44", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s largest known beaver dam?", "answer": "Alberta, Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b6", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Old Dominion\" state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1aa", "question": "What Elvis Presley film is set in England?", "answer": "Double Trouble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f8", "question": "Whose novel is the basis for the Lloyd Webber musical \"The Phantom of the Opera\"?", "answer": "Gaston Leroux's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be5", "question": "What two kinds of opera do the Arts recognize?", "answer": "Comic and Grand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c677", "question": "What inventor was known as the \"Wizard of Menlo Park\"?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5e726ce05a3942286e33", "question": "Beyonce's 2011 hit \"Party\" features which founding member of OutKast?", "answer": "Andre 3000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae87", "question": "What did the US government purchase from Spain in 1819?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a009", "question": "What color are Chip 'n' Dale's noses?", "answer": "Black and red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c596877e98cb977789b2", "question": "What marks the border between Asia and Africa?", "answer": "Suez Canal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b154", "question": "What 15th century Incan site was discovered in 1911 by Hiram Bingham?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f18", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Kirk Douglas and Tim Roth?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af255a5b63e5727cf5a483a", "question": "Australia\u2019s capital city, Canberra, is located in which territory?", "answer": "Australian Capital Territory", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ea", "question": "Which US state is named after a King of England?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cefc136948005ec986edce5", "question": "Who is the twelfth member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Olivia Hye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c9f76cb4e2c7fbd3896749", "question": "What company\u2019s tea shipment was destroyed during the Boston Tea Party in 1773?", "answer": "East India Company", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339543", "question": "Who hosted \"The Hollywood Squares\" between 1986 and 1989?", "answer": "John Davidson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e2", "question": "What US state's license plates sport the slogan \"First in Flight\"?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be50", "question": "What replaced the GameCube on November 19, 2006?", "answer": "The Wii", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590720a93745b36be73039f2", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Rockin\u2019 Around the Christmas Tree\" in 1958?", "answer": "Brenda Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f4", "question": "Which island boasts of being Napoleon's birthplace?", "answer": "Corsica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21f", "question": "What city was Tupac Shakur killed in?", "answer": "Las Vegas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f9", "question": "In which 1998 movie did the main character said \"You got the wrong guy. I'm the Dude, man.\"?", "answer": "The Big Lebowski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523f68736d4be723796b58", "question": "What year were the Canada's Juno Awards first awarded?", "answer": "1970", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391be", "question": "In which film did Paul Newman play a crime boss named John Rooney?", "answer": "Road to Perdition", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f4e3fa5fdd6dd25324e8", "question": "What country borders Central African Republic to the west?", "answer": "Cameroon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594a62742ebb971c1417fb8f", "question": "In which Olympic games did Nadia Com\u0103neci become the first gymnist to be awarded a perfect score of 10.0?", "answer": "1976 Olympic Games", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8a92301dd7bf43be5e748", "question": "Who is the patron saint of lost causes?", "answer": "St. Jude", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a335", "question": "What song has the lyric \"I saw a werewolf with a Chinese menu in his hand\"?", "answer": "Werewolves of London", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339009", "question": "What is the more common name for serigraphy?", "answer": "Screen printing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390bf", "question": "How is Samuel Langhorne Clemens better known?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb671b5dad637d903c883b", "question": "If you order \"murgh\" from the menu at an Indian restaurant, what meat will you get?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e1a506d333868d34d729", "question": "Which country did England send convicts to between 1788 and 1868?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1e", "question": "Which royal palace was damaged by fire in 1986?", "answer": "Hampton Court Palace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ce", "question": "Where was Enrico Caruso born?", "answer": "Naples, Italy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac9d", "question": "How many of Henry VIII's wives were executed?", "answer": "Two", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd6", "question": "What horse race was first held in 1875 at the Churchill Downs racetrack?", "answer": "Kentucky Derby", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd8213dd0de9af39e9d46a4", "question": "What was the original name for jeans?", "answer": "Waist overalls", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be18", "question": "Which modern instrument was called the sackbut until the nineteenth century?", "answer": "The trombone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b743", "question": "What is known as the \"Mary Celeste\"?", "answer": "A ship", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc8428378d18506ae1fe48c", "question": "Who was the front for the British band \"Dire Straits\"?", "answer": "Mark Knopfler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba1", "question": "At the head of which Gulf does Saint Petersburg lie?", "answer": "Gulf of Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a97ae61d1b4d384d5d687", "question": "What title has the wife of an Earl?", "answer": "Countess", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f169bbf7c52aae91cc07d4", "question": "Who played \"Hawkeye\" in the 1970 film \"MASH\"?", "answer": "Donald Sutherland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d23", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"National Velvet\"?", "answer": "Horse racing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b85ae662d71a53651022", "question": "Petroglyph is an engraving or image created on what?", "answer": "Stone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe772e2eec85e375820b302", "question": "Which mountain is depicted in Toblerone chocolate bars' logo?", "answer": "The Matterhorn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc23eec223966ae8f8873", "question": "Razzie awards are meant to go to bad movies, but who got nominated for directing the now widely respected film Scarface?", "answer": "Brian De Palma", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c613", "question": "Polaris is also referred to as what?", "answer": "The North Star", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c17a", "question": "What object is said to bring bad luck if it is broken?", "answer": "Mirror", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b64d", "question": "Irish coffee is made with what type of alcohol?", "answer": "Whiskey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02d", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", Stewie took captive the cast of which hit TV show?", "answer": "Star Trek: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a99cc61d1b4d384d5d69f", "question": "What tennis player earned the nickname the \"Ice Man\"?", "answer": "Bjorn Borg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8db", "question": "What is the name of the cord joining a mother and her unborn child?", "answer": "Umbilical cord", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a6", "question": "What plant does the Boll Weevil destroy?", "answer": "Cotton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdc7eec223966ae8f88f8", "question": "Who plays Marty Byrde in the TV drama series \"Ozark?\"", "answer": "Jason Bateman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c95", "question": "On what planet was Superman born?", "answer": "Krypton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd18c3129d03ab85b632b33", "question": "Who first said, \"Genius is one percent inspiration, ninety-nine percent perspiration\"?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5ef46ce05a3942286e3c", "question": "Who had a hit song with the theme from the movie \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Ray Parker, Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af256b3b63e5727cf5a483f", "question": "What popular toy, that is still widely used today, was invented by Arthur K. Melin in 1958?", "answer": "The Hula Hoop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010ca970775fa611bce67fb", "question": "What were chopsticks originally used for?", "answer": "Cooking -- Their length made them ideal for reaching deep into boiling pots of water or oil.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a1", "question": "What is a young female horse called?", "answer": "A filly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3d", "question": "What is the title object of the 2006 film \"Brick\" a brick of?", "answer": "Heroin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af30", "question": "From what terrible disease did Robert the Bruce suffer?", "answer": "Leprosy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fffa61c73838c5c8a417f2d", "question": "What is the process by which a Komodo Dragon can reproduce asexually?", "answer": "Parthenogenesis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fde5141c6c6b019850c9a8e", "question": "In the Bible, who was Jacob's daughter?", "answer": "Dinah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c63", "question": "What was Gatsby's first name in the book \"The Great Gatsby\u2019s\"?", "answer": "Jay", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c13", "question": "Who is the duo what created the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Trey Parker and Matt Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4bff49076251badbeacb", "question": "Which U.S. President had the most children?", "answer": "John Tyler -- The 10th president had 16 children \u2014 15 with his two wives and one born out of wedlock.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dba", "question": "Until their 2007 breakup, Peter Hook spent almost three decades as the bassist for what band?", "answer": "New Order", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51301ff04d658268c92d5", "question": "Where was Adolf Hitler born?", "answer": "Hitler was born in Braunau am Inn, a town in Austria-Hungary (present-day Austria)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba73", "question": "What Latin phrase is used meaning \u201can attorney representing a client for free\u201d?", "answer": "Pro bono", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590723043745b36be7303a04", "question": "Who directed the 2003 film \"Love Actually\"?", "answer": "Richard Curtis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c22e", "question": "Eclairs are said to have originated in which country?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c11c", "question": "What year did the US first host the Summer Olympic Games?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c73b877e98cb977789c9", "question": "Which national capital does the Vltava River flow through?", "answer": "Prague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a54f", "question": "Which US state is home to the Klamath Mountains?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b108", "question": "What 1990's Russian president had quintuple bypass surgery while in office?", "answer": "Boris Yeltsin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339452", "question": "What were the children allergic to in the movie \"The Others\"?", "answer": "Light", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba86", "question": "Whose likeness is depicted on the Purple Heart Award?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af24bb8844f4236002b95b0", "question": "The names of how many countries start with the letter \"A\"?", "answer": "12", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee8", "question": "What mythical title has been given to poets from Sappho to Anne Bradstreet?", "answer": "The Tenth Muse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe73ddfeec85e375820b26e", "question": "Plymouth is the capital of what territory?", "answer": "Montserrat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd8", "question": "What popular actor produced the show \"Entourage\"?", "answer": "Mark Wahlberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b30301dd7bf43be5e7a6", "question": "What flower symbolizes indifference according to the Old Farmer\u2019s Almanac?", "answer": "Candytuft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c5", "question": "Who produced two booklets for \"Comic Relief\" under the names Newt Scamander and Kennilworthy Whisp?", "answer": "J.K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff5139aff04d658268c92dd", "question": "The last execution in the Tower of London took place during what war?", "answer": "World War II\u00a0-- Josef Jakobs, a German soldier, was executed by firing squad on August 14, 1941 for espionage.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393fd", "question": "Who co-wrote, directed and starred in the 1971 movie \"Bananas\"?", "answer": "Woody Allen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b116", "question": "Who was the second man to set foot on the moon?", "answer": "Edwin \"Buzz\" Aldrin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339075", "question": "What is the name of the Egyptian goddess of the sky?", "answer": "Nut", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d6", "question": "Who created the original Star Trek series?", "answer": "Gene Roddenberry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a038", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", who unknowingly financed the publication of Peter's erotic novels?", "answer": "Carter Pewterschmidt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b968", "question": "On which wedding anniversary would you buy your partner leather?", "answer": "The 3rd", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd9", "question": "Lansing is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea43beff048f679a45ab87", "question": "What enzyme is responsible for breaking down starches?", "answer": "Amylase", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339420", "question": "Who plays the role of Mr. Brown in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f2", "question": "What mammal typically dies of starvation in the wild after its last set of teeth wear out?", "answer": "Elephant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389cf", "question": "What book of short stories has a second section called \"Kaa's Hunting\"?", "answer": "The Jungle Book", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b026", "question": "What Native American leader surrendered at Skeleton Canyon in 1886?", "answer": "Geronimo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5bab6ce05a3942286e18", "question": "What was the name of Bob Ross' TV show?", "answer": "\"The Joy of Painting\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b38106d333868d34d6d8", "question": "Who introduced potatoes into Ireland?", "answer": "Sir Walter Raleigh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96e2b23c87fd04dd15e34", "question": "What is the oldest sport in history?", "answer": "Wrestling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c781fbde8045e48466c3", "question": "What was the first masculine name given to a hurricane?", "answer": "Bob", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fde4d8dc6c6b019850c9a81", "question": "The beautiful Nefertiti was the wife of what Pharaoh?", "answer": "Akhenaten", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c311", "question": "What element are diamonds made of?", "answer": "Carbon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008e5fcf842fa4c4ba96b1", "question": "Which year was the \"Battle of Jutland\" fought?", "answer": "1916", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e77", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Places in the Heart\"?", "answer": "John Malkovich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ddc306d333868d34d708", "question": "In which developed nation was unemployment the highest in the 1920's?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c88b877e98cb977789e8", "question": "Where can you drive the Road to Hana?", "answer": "Maui, Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8d4ec2b42d4a3561a9efd", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is Darcy Parker\u2019s alias?", "answer": "Darcia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc6b", "question": "What year did Brett Favre officially retire from his football career?", "answer": "2011", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a533", "question": "The Missouri River flows into what river?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b28d", "question": "What bloodbath followed Henry of Navarre's 1572 wedding to Marguerite of Valois?", "answer": "The Saint Bartholomew's Day Massacre", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f168c7f7c52aae91cc07ca", "question": "John Simon Ritchie became famous under what name?", "answer": "Sid Vicious", "category": "entertainment"}]